Guide to the Rick Lazio Papers, 1981–2005
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series VI. Audio-Visual
  - TV Commercial – "AMO" Lazio For Senate 2000, 29 Oct 2000; (Video-VHS) (Box 10)
  - TV Commercial – "Strength and Independence" Lazio For Senate 2000, 29 Oct 2000; (Video-VHS) (Box 10)
  - Lazios on Larry King Live, 1 Nov 2000; (Video-VHS) (Box 10)
  - Lazios on Larry King Live, 1 Nov 2000; (Video-VHS) (Box 10)
  - TV Commercial – "Video" Lazio For Senate 2000, 2 Nov 2000; (Video-VHS) (Box 10)
  - TV Commercial – "Point" Lazio For Senate 2000, 3 Nov 2000; (Video-VHS) (Box 10)
  - O’Reilly Factor, 27 Dec 2000; (Video-VHS) (Box 10)
  - Scott Howell and Co., Demo Reel, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 10)
  - Columbus Day Parade NYC, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 10)
  - Lazio 2000 Debate 1, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 10)
  - Lazio 2000 Debate 2, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 10)
  - Lazio 2000 Debate 3, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - Lazio Rep. Con., undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - CNN – Bush/Gore, R.L./H.C, MSNBC – Tom Reynolds Hardball, CH 2 R.L./H.C. Campaign 2000, Ch 7 Same, Ads Extra Friends H.C., undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - The Truth, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - R.L. on Fox and Friends and Fox News, 27 Feb 2001; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - Cavuto On Business, 1 Sep 2001; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - Do Not Remove from Bullpen, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - Hannay Reels: The Reel Story, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - Hillary "The Street Where I Live,", undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - Master Tape #3, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - Pearl Harbor Special, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - R.L. Interview/Election Night, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - Tape 7, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - The View, 18 Oct [no year]; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - To The Lazio Family c/o Steve Castleton, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - Weekend Backup – CBS 2, UPN 9, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 11)
  - Case Study Reel, Issues: Homelessness, Life, Political, Short Films, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - CH 7 – 11 News Tape, Elec. Night, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - Columbus Day Parade (4), undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - CSPAN Nov. 10 HOR, 10 Nov [no year]; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - Empire State… Speech, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - Kidney Cancer Association "Salute to Rick Lazio, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - News Tape #2, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - News Tape 4, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - News Tape 6, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - Our Contributions: The Italians In America, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - Peter King – Hard Ball, Brian Williams – Cong. Reynolds, 9 Oct [no year]; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - Questioning of Starr by Schippers, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - R.L. Press Conference, 11 Aug [no year]; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - RAW Ch. 4, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - Rep. Rick Lazio’s "View From the Hill", With Dr. Richard Klausner, National Cancer Institute, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - Weekend Backup Tape, CNN Channel 10, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 12)
  - (no label), undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - A Request for Clemency For Marie La Pinta, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - Bill Clinton Testimony Various Channels, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - CNN – Day After Clinton/Lazio Debate, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - Cong. Rick Lazio: Overhauling America’s Housing Policy, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - Dave Evans Highlights, ABC 7, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - History of North Virginia, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - Housing Reforms – Floor Remarks (104th), undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - Inside Education (RL appears), undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - Kidney Cancer Association "Salute to R.L., Bob Wallace Prod., undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - News 12 – Childhood Cancer Series (Forum and Camp), 16-17 Sep [no year]; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - Schumer Quote, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - Tape Five, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - View From The Hill: Sagamore Hill, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - Zev Brenner Original Copy, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 13)
  - (no label), undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - "This Week" with Sam Donaldson and Cokie Roberts – Lazio, 23 Sep [no year]; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - BDC on Fox, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - Channel 55, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - Childhood, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - D-Day Ceremonies at Fire Island and Lasalle Academy, 6 Jun [no year]; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - Insurance Broadcast System – Features RL Bill on Insurance Availability For Homeowners, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - Master Tape #1, 14 Jul-15 Aug [no year]; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - News Programs, 14 Jul-15 Aug [no year]; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - Newsday "Long Island…Our Story", undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - Pataki Rally, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - RL at Parade Near Beginning, Republican National Convention, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - Weekend Backup – ABC 7 – Election Day Coverage, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - WPIX – Alcohol Abuse Prevention Public Service Campaign, Congressman Lazio, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - WPIX-11 – Marvin Scott Show "Polls", undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 14)
  - (no label), undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 15)
  - Constitution Day, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 15)
  - Image Maint. Ltd. "Lazio", 3 Oct [no year]; (Video- Beta) (Box 15)
  - Lazio Footage, undated; (Video tape) (Box 15)
  - Pilgrim Films "Lazio For Congress" Hour 1, undated; (Video-Beta) (Box 15)
  - Pilgrim Films "Lazio For Congress" Hour 2, undated; (Video-Beta) (Box 15)
  - Pilgrim Films "Lazio For Congress" Hour 3, undated; (Video-Beta) (Box 15)
  - Senator Robert Dole on RL, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 15)
  - Weekend Backup – NY 1, Fox 5, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 15)
  - Pataki/Lazio Rally CAM 1 #2, 30 Oct 1994; (Video-Beta) (Box 16)
  - Pataki/Lazio Rally CAM 2 #2, 30 Oct 1994; (Video-Beta) (Box 16)
  - Fox News Sunday, undated; (Video-Beta) (Box 16)
  - Show Open: "A View From The Hill" with Rick Lazio, undated; (Video-Beta) (Box 16)
  - TV Commercial – (32) Lazio For Senate 2000, Jun-Nov 2000; (CD) (Box 16)
  - TV Commercial – (32) Lazio For Senate 2000, Jun-Nov 2000; (CD) (Box 16)
  - Fire Island Forum (tape 1) (see: Suffolk County Legislature, Fire Island Forum, 1992), 14 Sep 1992; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - Fire Island Forum (tape 2) (see: Suffolk County Legislature, Fire Island Forum, 1992), 14 Sep 1992; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - "Lazio Senate Candidacy Postponement Press Conference," (attached to unprocessed slides), 11 Aug 1999; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - "Allegany County GOP Lunch Speech," and Chautaqua County Speech - Dennis Goggin," (attached to unprocessed slides), 18 Sep 1999; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - Reporters Roundtable, (attached to unprocessed slides), 4 Jan 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - Radio Commercial – "Ancestors" Lazio For Senate 2000, 31 Aug 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - Radio Commercial – "Delivers" Lazio For Senate 2000, 2 Oct 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - Radio Commercial – "Elect" Lazio For Senate 2000, 3 Oct 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - Radio Commercial – "American Dream" Lazio For Senate 2000, 6 Oct 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - Radio Commercial – "Extreme" Lazio For Senate 2000, 20 Oct 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - Radio Commercial – "Hospitals Buffalo" Lazio For Senate 2000, 20 Oct 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - Radio Commercial – "Extreme" Lazio For Senate 2000, 24 Oct 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - Radio Commercial – "Ancestors" Lazio For Senate 2000, 31 Oct 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - Radio Commercial – "Extreme" Lazio For Senate 2000, 31 Oct 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - Radio Commercial – "Join Me" Lazio For Senate 2000, 31 Oct 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - Radio Commercial – "Hospitals: Buffalo Rev." Lazio For Senate 2000, 31 Oct 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - no label (attached to unprocessed slides), undated; (Audio Cassette) (Box 161 (Oversize))
  - Commercial Edit Rick Lazio, (Solo, With Family), undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - Commercials, Do Not Tape Over, (Political Ads), undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - Debate II – CNN, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - Kidney Cancer Association "Salute To Rick Lazio,", undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - Master Tape Copy, (2 RL Ads, 1 PL Ad), undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - Newt Gingrich On RL, GOP TV, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - Rep. Rick Lazio’s "View From The Hill" W/ Dr. Richard Klausner, National Cancer Institute, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - Republican National Committee, "Lets Be Clear", RNC95-TV-83, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - "Revolution", One Year To Victory, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - "Rolls Rumble" (? Not Entirely Legible ?), undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - Shimmering Heart, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - Take Control USA, 45 Minute Demonstration Copy, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - Tom Hansen, Debate, undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - Republican National Committee, "Level With The American People", RNC95-TV-96, 19 Dec 1995; (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - Lazio For Congress 1996 Television Highlights, (Video-VHS) (Box 17)
  - Lazio For Congress, "Protecting Our Shoreline" Revised, 18 Oct 1996; (Video-VHS) (Box 18)
  - Power, Politics and You Election Night Special, Smithtown Sheraton, 5 Nov 1996; (Video-VHS) (Box 18)
  - Foster Grandparents Promo PSA with Congressman Rick Lazio, May 1998; (Video-VHS) (Box 18)
  - Rick Lazio For Congress, "Getting The Job Done,", 8 Oct 1998; (Video-VHS) (Box 18)
  - Rick Lazio For Congress, "Getting The Job Done,", 14 Oct 1998; (Video-VHS) (Box 18)
  - Rick Lazio For Congress, "Getting The Job Done,", 14 Oct 1998; (Video-VHS) (Box 18)
  - Congressman Rick Lazio rings the Opening Bell, 13 Dec 1999; (Video-VHS) (Box 18)
  - Lazio 2000, (5 30-second Commercials and Rough Cut Folklore/Parade, 4 Endorsements…Diaz-Balart, Badillo, Calderon, Mascaro, and Montage), (Video-VHS) (Box 18)
  - "Rick Lazio/Hillary Clinton" Eyewitness News, WABC-TV New York, 26 Jul 2000; (Video-VHS) (Box 18)
  - "Rick Lazio" Inside Politics – CNN, Eyewitness News – WABC, Close Up – NY1, 14 Aug 2000; (Video-VHS) (Box 18)
  - "This Week" with Sam Donaldson and Cokie Roberts, 24 Sep 2000; (Video-VHS) (Box 18)
  - "Rick Lazio" The View – ABC, 10-11 Oct 2000; (Video-VHS) (Box 18)
  - The View – ABC…mentions upcoming Lazio appearance, 13 Oct 2000; (Video-VHS) (Box 18)
  - "Interview with Rick Lazio, RNN Presentation Video,", 4 Aug 2000; (Video-VHS) (Box 166)
  - "Lazio for Senate 2000 'Introduction' RLFS-0601," The Murphy Pintak Gautier Hudome Agency (attached to unprocessed photos of senate campaign activities), copy 1, (Video-VHS) (Box 166)
  - "Lazio for Senate 2000 'Introduction' RLFS-0601," The Murphy Pintak Gautier Hudome Agency (attached to unprocessed photos of senate campaign activities), copy 2, (Video-VHS) (Box 166)
  - no label, (attached to unprocessed photos of senate campaign activities), undated; (Video-VHS) (Box 166)
  - From The Hill with Rick Lazio, undated; (Video-Beta) (Box 19)
  - Gregg Cockrell…, undated; (Audio Cassette) (Box 19)
  - Rick Lazio and Tom Downey Debate, "Good Morning Long Island,", undated; (Audio Cassette) (Box 19)
  - NAB PSAs, Patricia Lazio, (Breast Cancer, Prostate Cancer, Drunk Driving, 1993; (Reel) (Box 19)
  - NAB PSAs, Patricia Lazio, (Breast Cancer, Prostate Cancer, Drunk Driving, 1993; (Reel) (Box 19)
  - Joyce Keller Show, WGBB 1240AM, (2nd Half: Soupy Soles and Hon. Rick Lazio), 22 Jun 1994; (Audio Cassette) (Box 19)
  - Lazio For Congress Television Highlights, 1996; (Video-Beta) (Box 19)
  - LIA Executive Award Breakfast Tape 1, 14 Jul 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 19)
  - LIA Executive Award Breakfast Tape 2, 14 Jul 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 19)
  - LIA Executive Award Breakfast Tape 3, 14 Jul 2000; (Audio Cassette) (Box 19)
  - Photographs, (Unprocessed) (Box 167-170)
- Series VII. Artifacts
  - Pre-Congressional Papers
    - Give Away – Pins, "Elect Lazio, Legislator,", 1989 (Box 159)
    - Give Away – Emery Board, "Re-elect Rick Lazio, Legislator,", undated (Box 159)
    - Give Away – Hair Comb, "Rick Lazio County Legislator,", undated (Box 159)
  - Congressional Papers
    - License plates, Inaugural Plates, 1994 (Box 159)
    - Give Away – Bubble Gum, Cigar-shaped, "I Love Lazio,", undated (Box 159)
    - Give Away – Pin, "Rick Lazio for New York,", undated (Box 159)
    - Give Away – Pins, Spanish Language, "Rick Lazio for New York,", undated (Box 159)
    - Plaque, with mounted leather whip, "Rick Lazio, 106th Congress, Whip Team, The Year We Stopped The Raid,", undated (Box 160 (Oversize))
    - Guest Book, 1993-1996 (Box 162)
    - Guest Book, 1996-1999 (Box 162)
    - Guest Book, 1999-2000 (Box 162)
  - Senate Campaign Papers
    - Give Away – Balloons, "Rick Lazio for Senate,", 2000 (Box 159)
    - Give Away – Baseball Cap, "Lazio for Senate,", 2000 (Box 160 (Oversize))
    - Give Away – Kerchief, "Lazio, 100% New York,", 2000 (Box 160 (Oversize))